Guide to the Wendell Ricketts papers, circa 1961-2004.
Ricketts, Wendell papers, circa 1961-2004.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Wendell Ricketts papers, circa 1961-2004
7681
Wendell Ricketts
13.9 cubic feet
Subject files, publications, photographs, audiocassettes, videotapes, photo slides.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files on lesbian and gay parents, foster parents, and adoptive parents, and on various lesbian and gay family issues and children's and youth issues. Also, files on AIDS, especially in San Francisco in the early 1980s; files on various gay rights issues, including the murder of Harvey Milk; and files from work with "Drummer" magazine, including gay erotic photographs. Includes numerous newspaper clippings.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files on lesbian and gay parents, foster parents, and adoptive parents, and on various lesbian and gay family issues and children's and youth issues. Also, files on AIDS, especially in San Francisco in the early 1980s; files on various gay rights issues, including the 1978 murder of Harvey Milk; correspondence with writers and artists and drafts of their work; and files from his work with "Drummer" magazine, including gay erotic photographs.
Also, slides of an ACT UP demonstration, probably 1992, in San Francisco protesting price-gouging by Astra Pharmaceuticals for its drug Foscarnet/Foscavir (ganciclovir), at the time one of the only therapies for CMV- blindess. And slides of a May 22, 1994 ACT-UP demonstration at the San Francisco Federal Building about the AIDS Cure Act.
Information about and writings of Massimo Consoli, an Italian writer, archivist, theorist, known as the founder of the Italian gay movement.
Information about Robert Rosenkrantz and his case, correspondence between Rosenkrantz and Wendell Ricketts, and some photographs. Rosenkrantz, shortly after high school graduation, killed another recent graduate for revealing Rosenkrantz's homosexuality to his parents. Robert was convicted of second-degree murder and sentenced to seventeen years to life in prison. Although Robert is reported to have behaved as a model prisoner, he was rejected several times for parole, based on the harsh standards for life-sentenced prisoners held by then-Governor of California Gray Davis. Significant among these files are examples of prison art, including approximately 20 elaborately-decorated envelopes of letters addressed to prisoners' lawyers, as well as several larger drawings.
Series I. Lesbian/Gay Parenting contains files relating to lesbian and gay parenting and foster care. Many of the files are background materials for the book, Gays & Lesbians as Foster Parents, written by Wendell Ricketts in conjunction with the University of Southern Maine's National Child Welfare Center.
Series II. Pornography Research contains files from a research project done by Ricketts about the language used in popular gay pornographic/erotic literature. Also, there are miscellaneous files relating to general research into pornography.
Series III. AIDS Resource Files contains miscellaneous AIDS research materials, including files on specific people and events, such as the AIDS Quilt and the Names Project.
Series IV. Subject Files contains general files on mostly lesbian and gay related issues, including materials on specific people and groups. Many of the news articles written by Ricketts and the background/research material for each article are contained in this series, including transcripts of some of the interviews done by Ricketts. Also included is correspondence from/to Ricketts about book reviews, articles, etc.
Series V. Erotic Photographs contains numerous photographs, mainly black and white prints, of male models. They are in relation to Ricketts' work with Drummer magazine. The majority of the photos are by Target Studios. They are filed alphabetically by model.
Series VI. contains various audiocassettes, mainly interviews done by Wendell Ricketts. A more detailed description of the various cassette tapes from Wendell Ricketts is included in Box 10. Also included is one videocassette.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ricketts, Wendell.; Consoli, Massimo.; Rosenkrantz, Robert.; ACT UP-San Francisco (organization)
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease)--Political activity.; Foster parents--United States.; Gay parents--United States.; Homosexuality.; Prisoners as artists.; Pornography.; Sadomasochism.
Form and Genre Terms:
Erotica.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Two folders of correspondence have been RESTRICTED until 2013 and 2022, repectively. They are currently located in the accession folder.
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Materials are arranged according to the original folder headings, when present. Series have been created based on the original groupings of the files.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Lesbian/Gay Parenting
Boxes 1-2, 11-12
Commonwealth of Massachusetts
Lesbian Rights Project
University of Southern Maine Book Project
Series II. Pornography Research
Box 2
Pornography Popular Literature Research Project
Series III. AIDS Resource Files
Boxes 3-5, 12
Series IV. Subject Files
Boxes 6-8, 11-16
Everything I Have is Blue: Short Fiction by Working-Class Men about More-or-Less Gay Life, edited by Wendell Ricketts
Research: Copies of Professional Papers
Sadism/Masochism
University of Hawaii Files
Drummer magazine lawsuit
Series V. Erotic Photographs
Box 9, 11
Series VI. Audiovisual Materials
Box 10-12
Audiotapes
Videotapes
Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Lesbian/Gay Parenting
  - Adoption/Foster Care: Lesbian & Gay, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adoption & Foster Parenting for Lesbians & Gay Men by Wendell Ricketts & Roberta Achtenberg (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Adoptive and Foster Gay Parent", by Wendell Ricketts, chapter from Alternative Families, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Advocate article search, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Psychological Association Professional Policy Statements, 1988 (?) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barrister: Family Law Article, by Donna Hitchens and Wendell Ricketts, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Batey Case News Clipping, Nov. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies: Gay related (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Birth Certificates & Adoption (San Francisco), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Boston Case - Settlement, April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Boston Foster Care Case, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bozett: Foster/Adoptive Chapter, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cain, P: Litigating for Lesbian/Gay Rights: A Legal History, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts
    - Thomas Morse's Memo & Order of Motion, Aug. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Complaint of Babets, Jean, Jan. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Proceedings of Speakout, List of Participants, Written Comments, Dec. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Settlement Agreement re: Status Report on Foster Care, Dec. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Report of Legislative Subcommittee on Foster Care, Dec. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dept. of Public Welfare Report on Admin. Case Reviews, March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Curiale case (adoption), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - DHHS Report on youth suicide, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Families: various statistics, articles, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Foster care & adoption, general/national information, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Gay & Lesbian Parents Coalition International (GLPCI Network), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Halley, Janet: The Politics of the Closet: Equal Protection for Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual Identity, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Hardwick, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Hinman v. Dept. of Personnel Affairs, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Hitchens/Davis adoption case (San Francisco), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Hitchens, Donna, presiding judge of S.F. Superior Court, article about, re: family court changes, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - In re: Charles B. (Ohio adoption case), 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Lesbian/gay parenting and family, general information, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
  - Lesbian/gay parenting group, sponsered by Lyon-Martin, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Lesbian Rights Project
    - General information (includes some photographs), 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Benefit, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Quietly Making History, article by Wendell Ricketts, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Artie Wallace press conference, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - New articles re: gay parent's legal rights, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Who may adopt?" notes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Interviews, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Article by Wendell Ricketts, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Lesbian and Gay Parenting: A Psychological and Legal Perspective. By Roberta Achtenberg. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Preserving and Protecting the Families of Lesbians and Gay Men. By Roberta Achtenberg., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Recognizing Lesbian and Gay Families: Strategies for Extending Employment Benefit Coverage. By Teresa Lynn Friend and Pamela Liberty., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Lesbian Mothers and their Children: An Annotated Bibliography of Legal and Psychological Materials. 2nd edition., 1983 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Legal Issues in Donor Insemination., 1984 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - A Lesbian and Gay Parents' Legal Guide to Child Custody. National Center for Lesbian Rights., 1989 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Lesbians Choosing Motherhood: Legal Implications of Donor Insemination and Co-Parenting. 2nd edition. Maria Gil de Lamadrid (ed.); National Center for Lesbian Rights (U.S.)., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - National Center for Lesbian Rights, 1991, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous notes and articles (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Miller, Brian: Gay fathers material, incl. Gay Father's Forum publication, 1979, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - New Hampshire State Policies, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Polikoff, Nancy: This Child Does Have Two Mothers, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Potomac news - adoption (includes article by Ricketts), 1984, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - President's Task Force on Adoption, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Quayle, Dan: "Family Values", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reproductive Issues/Parenting, 1987-1988, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sabol v. Bowling, (lesbian custody battle), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco Chronicle index, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sarafino, Edward P., An Estimate of Nationwide Incidence of Sexual Offenses Against Children, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sue Pavlic-Millie Jessen-Eric adoption case, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Triangle Project (helping lesbian/gay youth), 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Triangle Project (includes article by Ricketts), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - University of Southern Maine Book Project
    - Interviews/contacts, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Draft one of Gays & Lesbians as Foster Parents, 1988? (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Drafts/notes/ideas re: "Foster Parent" publication, 1988? (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gays & Lesbians as Foster Parents manuscript, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bibliographies, references, and notes, 1989? (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - National Child Welfare Center- correspondence, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - NCWC- teleconference information, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Reference notes (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Springer v. Graham-Newlin court case, circa 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 4-7)
  - Early v. Griffith court case, circa 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
  - Maine Dept. of Health Services adoption study, March 1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Law notes/cases (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Co-Parent Forum-civil code revisions (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Children of Lesbians and Gays Everywhere (COLAGE) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Kids' Talk (published by Center Kids), 1990-1997 (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
  - Chain of Life (adoption reform newsletter) (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Series II. Pornography Research
  - Various articles/publications from popular media, 1980, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Various articles/publications from popular media, 1985-1986, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Scholarly publications, 1981, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Scholarly articles/publications, 1971, 1978-1979, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Pornography Popular Literature Research Project
    - Sex scene synopses (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Research results summary (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Presentation materials, 1981? (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - References and notes (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Notes, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bibliographies (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series III. AIDS Resource Files
  - ACT-UP news clippings, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Africa: news clippings, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Africa: Handbook for AIDS Prevention in Africa draft, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Africa: miscellaneous, includes AIDSCOM information, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AIDS Apartheid, by Charles Barker, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AIDS Conference San Francisco materials, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - AIDS Conference Amsterdam materials, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - AIDS Conference Yokohama materials, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - AIDS Fraud Task Force, 1991? (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - AIDS in the 1990s: Art, Analysis, Action, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - AIDS newspaper clippings, circa 1983-1996 (Box 3, Folder 12-26)
  - Animal model questions/hypotheses, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Articles on AIDS: Rolling Stone, Harpers, Newsweek, various SF magazines, 1985-1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Articles on AIDS: causes and cures, conspiracies, in mainstream press, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Ashe, Arthur, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bagley, Louis, (author of As Max Saw It), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Bergalis, Kimberly, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "Be There For The Cure" SAFC campaign, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Benetton ad campaign, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Bibliographies (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Brodkey, Harold, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Brother's Network (safe sex) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Casimir, Bart, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - CDC materials, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - CDC surveillance criteria (includes report), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Cell-mutated immunity/pathinogenesis, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Chow, Tina, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - City magazine AIDS piece, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Community prescription service, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Compound Q - GLQ223, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Condoms, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Crewdson, John, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Cuba, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - d4T, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Dance Envisions the Cure", 1995 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Davis, Brad, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - DIFFA: Design Industry Foundation Fighting AIDS, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - DNCB, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Doonesbury cartoon AIDS series (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Driscoll, Jim, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Duesberg, Dr. Peter, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ebola virus, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Elders, Jocelyn, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fauci, Anthony, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Frenc Blood Scandal, 1992? (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gallo, Dr. Robert, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gebbie, Kristine, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Getty, Aileen, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - GMHC (Gay Men's Health Crisis), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - God's Love We Deliver (Ganga Stone), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Good Dog Campaign: SFAF, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - GRID/AIDS: pamphlets, newsletters, articles, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - Hawaii, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hemlock Society Newsletter, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hepatitis C Virus, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Heterosexual AIDS Information Special Interest group, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - HIV testing and theory criticism, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Insurance cash-in programs, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Johnson, Magic, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Latino AIDS Project, information on Ojos Que No Ven, (includes article by Ricketts), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Leprosy and HIV (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Long-term survivors, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Long-term survivor Out magazine project, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
  - Louganis, Greg, 1988, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Malaria/malaria treatment therapy, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - McClintock Project (AIDS Cure/ACT UP), 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 31-33)
  - McKean, Aldyn, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Media and AIDS, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Medicinal science, general information and mistakes (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Milligan, Michael article (by Ricketts), drafts (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Milligan, Michael-photos, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous AIDS articles, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Montagnier, Luc, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Mullis, Kary, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - MUREX: 10-minute AIDS test, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Names Project--Article by Wendell Ricketts, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Names Project/AIDS Quilt miscellany, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Names Project/AIDS Quilt news clippings, 1987-1989? (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Names Project Exposed: What Cleve Jones Doesn't Want You To Know (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Names Project volunteer information, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters (MIRA, PI Perspective, Critical Path AIDS Project, Positive News), 1990, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - New York Native articles, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Nucleoside Analogues- AZT, ddI, ddC, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Online AIDS Resources, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Opportunistic Infections, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Oral interferon, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Oral transmission of HIV (includes article by Ricketts), 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Outside the USA, 1990, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Ozone/oxidation, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Patient Zero" Advocate issue, 5/16/1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia the movie, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - POZ, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Prisoners, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Project Inform (includes numerous issues of PI Perspective, 1989-1996 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - Quarantine, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - QW Delaney/Gallo/Duesberg article drafts, by Ricketts, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Reappraising AIDS newsletter, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Resources for HIV+, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Ribavirin, 1987, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Risk Assessment, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Rist, Darrell Yates, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Rose, G. Steven (Boston), 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Schmalz, Jeffrey, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Schuklenk, Udo (dissident), 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Shilts, Randy, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Sonnabend, Dr. Joseph, 1989, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Staley, Peter, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Statistics and miscellaneous information, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "Stop AIDS" project materials, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Surrogate markers CD4t, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Survival Long Term (newsletter), from Ken Dickinson, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Suspicious treatments/frauds/quack cures, 1988-1992 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - TAG list [treatment action group], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - TAG report: Basic Research on HIV Infection, by Gregg Gonsalves, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Texas Department of Corrections: Inmates with HIV/AIDS, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Texas Department of Corrections: Inmates with HIV/AIDS, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Theater: "Healing Metaphors: The Theatre of AIDS," article by Wendell Ricketts, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Treatments-miscellaneous information, 1990, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Trials information, including AIDS Clinical Trials Group (ACTG), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Tuberculosis, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Various AIDS pamphlets, 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Various AIDS publications, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Women and HIV/AIDS (includes W.O.R.L.D. publication), 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Zamora, Pedro, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - AASECT notes, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Achtenberg, Roberta and Benjamin Morgan, photograph (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - AIDS and gay movement articles, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Allison, Dorothy, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Almodovar, Pedro, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Alternate magazine, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ammiano, Tom, election materials, circa 2003 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Andrews, Nancy: Family: A Portrait of Gay and Lesbian America, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Anti-gay violence/defamation, 1978-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Archives-lesbian and gay, 1981, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bacon, Francis, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Baldwin, James, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - BAR 25th anniversary history issue notes and research, 1996? (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bathhouse closures (San Francisco), 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bauman, Robert, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Belkin, Alan- Why I Want a Lover, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bense, Buzz, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Berube, Alan, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Besecker, Joe, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bieber, Irving, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Biological theories/research on homosexuality, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Blood Brothers--Ish 2, Summer 1999 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Boitano, Brian, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Boy George, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Boy with Arms Akimbo, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Branding, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Brock, David, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Broughton, James, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Brown, Rita Mae, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Brown, Tina, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Bryant, Anita, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Califia, Pat, 1992-1995, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
  - Cher, 1988, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Chester, Alfred, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Consoli, Massimo, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Core, Philip (erotic artist), 1988 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Coupland, Douglas, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - COYOTE (prostitute's rights group), 1987, 1989, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Cronenberg, David, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Cuba- various publications, including The Progressive, Mother Jones, Cuba Update, and Vanity Fair, 1977, 1988-1991, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Cuba- the Venceremos Brigade, 1977, 1981, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
  - Cunningham, Michael, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Deitch, Donna, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Drummer magazine debacle, 1994? (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Edward the Dyke and other poems, by Judy Grahn, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Erotic cards/postcards, including special occasions such as Valentine's Day, Birthdays, etc. (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Everything I Have is Blue: Short Fiction by Working-Class Men about More-or-Less Gay Life, edited by Wendell Ricketts
    - Suspect Thoughts Press, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Banner, Keith, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Cole, C. Bard, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Conrad, C.A., 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Devon, Marcel (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Feely, Rick (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hyatt, Martin, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Weir, John, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Additional materials, 1999-2004 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Everything I Have is Blue, draft, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - FOIA requests/information, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Foucault, Michel, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Frank, Barney, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 39)